Guide to the Acacia Fraternity records,1906-2007.
Acacia Fraternity records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Acacia Fraternity records, 1906-2007.
37-4-1538
Acacia Fraternity. Cornell Chapter.
17.7 cubic feet
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Acacia was founded in 1904 by 14 Master Masons at the University of Michigan. Today it is a strong international fraternity, with Chapters at over 40 universities across the United States and one in Canada. Over 41,000 university men have called themselves Acacians, including prominent figures such as Senators, university presidents, state governors, and Nobel Laureates. Famous Acacia alumni include: President William Howard Taft, William Jennings Bryan, Cliff Hillegas (founder of Cliff's Notes), Wes Santee (former Gold Medal distance runner), and Harold Edgerton (Nobel Prize in Physics).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes Acacia Fraternity Corporation Board of Directors minutes, correspondence, and financial reports, correspondence, alumni and membership records, fraternity rush material, constitutions and by-laws, meeting minutes, financial records, photographs, The Traveler (the alumni publication of the Acacia Fraternity, Cornell Chapter), TRIAD (the journal), building documents, architectural sketches and plans, and ledgers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Acacia Fraternity.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Acacia Fraternity at Cornell / Thomas J. Balcerski. Ithaca, N.Y., 2007; Acacia Fraternity Constitution and By-Laws. [S. l.], 1907; Journal of Acacia, Volumes 1-4; Wayne Heebner Rothenberger papers, 1908-1913; Thomas J. Balcerski Acacia Fraternity Papers, 2007, collection #6583; Acacia Fraternity, Cornell chapter [videorecording]: 100 years of brotherhood / director/producer, Paul Molnar. Other Acacia material may be found in the Karl M. Dallenbach papers, #2958.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Reports
Box 1
Series II. Chapter Operations National
Box 2
Series III. Chapter Operations Local
Boxes 2-4, 21, 23, 24
Series IV. Corporation
Boxes 4, 5, 24
Series V. Photographs
Boxes 5, 6, 7
Series VI. Chapter Meeting Minutes (CMM)
Box 8, 24
Series VII. Publications: Traveler
Boxes 8, 9
Series VIII. TRIAD, Journal
Boxes 10, 11
Series IX. Chapter Membership Records
Box 12
Series X. Brother Membership Files
Boxes 12-14
Series XI. Wing Building Documents and Architectural Sketches
Box 14
Series XII. Alumni Mailing Cards, #1-854
Box 15
Series XIII. Architectural Sketches, Blueprints, and Reproductions of Deeds and Other Documents
Boxes 17, 19, Mss. Collection Box 44
Series XIV. Ledgers
Box 18
Series XV. Masonic Literature
Box 20
Series XVI. National Interfraternity Conference Minutes
Box 20
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Board of Directors Meeting Minutes and Reports
  - Minutes and Reports (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Spiral Notebook Minute Book (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acacia Fraternity, Inc., Record of Incorporation (reproduction) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II. Chapter Operations National, 1907-1943
  - Cornell Org. Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Associations, Various (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chapter Alumni Directory and Membership Rolls (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapter Business (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondences, Other (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Masonic Communications (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondences Outside (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Corporation Docs, 1909-1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - War Records (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Treasures Reports, Seneca Street (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Steward Dept. Statements, Seneca Street (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Officer Reports, Seneca Street (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Badge Orders (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Financial Records (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Secretary Publications & Cards (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Acacia Store & Smoke Shop, Seneca Street (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Corporation Docs (Treasurer) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Constitution & By-Laws (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Bank Statements (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bills 708 Seneca Street House (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Promotional Materials, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cornell, Other (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chapter - Brotherhood (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Membership Rolls (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - National Com., 1907-1910 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - National Correspondence, 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Correspondence, 1911-1912 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - National Correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - National Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - National Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - National Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - National Correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - National Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - National Correspondence, 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - National Correspondence, 1920-1921 PART I (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - National Correspondence, 1920-1921, PART II (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - National Correspondence, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - National Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - National Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - California Chapter - Berkeley, CA (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Carnegie Chapter - Pittsburgh, PA (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Chicago (Ayin) Chapter - Chicago, IL (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Colorado Chapter - Boulder, CO (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Columbia Chapter - New York, NY (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Denver Chapter - Denver, CO (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Gauge & Gavel Fraternity - Pulman, WA (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Franklin Chapter - Philadelphia, PA (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - George Washington Chapter - Washington, DC (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Harvard Chapter - Cambridge, MA (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Illinois Chapter - Champaign, IL (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Indiana Chapter - Bloomington, Ind. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Iowa Chapter - Iowa City, Iowa (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Iowa State Chapter - Ames, Iowa (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Kansas Chapter (Gimel) - Lawrence, KS (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Kansas State Chapter - Manhattan, KS (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Michigan Chapter (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Minnesota Chapter - Minneapolis, Minn. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Missouri Chapter - Columbia, MO (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Nebraska Chapter - Lincoln, Nebr. (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - North Carolina Chapter - Chapel Hill, N.C. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Northwestern Chapter - Evanston, IL (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Ohio Chapter - Columbus, OH (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Ohio State Chapter - Columbus, OH (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Oklahoma Chapter - Norman, OK (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Oregon State Chapter - Corballis, OR (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Penn State Chapter - State College, PA (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Purdue Chapter - Lafayette, IN (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - RPI Chapter - Troy, NY (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Alumni Association - Los Angeles, CA (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Stanford (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Syracuse Chapter - Syracuse, NY (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Texas Chapter - Austin, TX (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Texas A&M (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Washington Chapter - Seattle, WA (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Wisconsin Chapter - Madison, Wis (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Yale Chapter - New Haven, CN (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Petition to Acacia Masonic Fraternity of Indiana University (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Series III. Chapter Operations Local, 1946-2007
  - Cornell Acacia Rush Books (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Cornell Acacia Rush Books (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Acacia Rush Information and Other Chapters (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Rush Materials (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - The Inside Story of Rush - 1970s (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Pledge Info, (1983; 1991; 1997-2001) (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Pledge Manuals, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Pledge Manuals (Northcote), 1992- (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Pledge Manuals (Northcote), 1992- (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Pledge Manuals, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pledge Education - Study Guides (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Phone Duties, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Excellence Packet (Pledge Education) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - OFSA Leadership Packet, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Hazing (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Letters to Brothers & Parents, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Senior Dean Ideas; FAW/Hell Week, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Acacia Songs (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ritual (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Parliamentary Procedures (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bylaws; Constitution; Amendments, 1988; 1991, 2001, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - House Policies (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Publications (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Daily Sun notice of chapter reorganization, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - AFF Annual Reports, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Party Concerns (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Summer Parties (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Social Calendar, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Social Calendar, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Human Service (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Scholarship (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cooks' Contracts (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Letter to Alumni (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Brotherhood Tree (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Homecoming (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Communications, Cornell (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Inspections, Cornell, Cayuga Heights (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondences, Outside (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Foster Home, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Cayuga Heights Governance, 1980s-90s (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Neighborhood Affairs, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Greetings, Postcards (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Chapter Adviser's Letters (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - VD Gold Book, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Thompson Fund (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Wayne Kuhn Fraternityship (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - AFF Cornell Chapter Fund, 1990-2007 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - AEF/AFF Scholarship Information, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - AFF Scholarship Information, 1999-2007 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Meeting Cost of College, Cornell Prizes, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National Correspondences, 1980-2007 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - National Statements, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Consultants' Reports (National) - Troubled Times (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Petitions of Colonies (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Acacia Journal, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - National Updates, 1986-2002 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Acacia National Conclave Materials, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Acacia National Conclave Materials, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Acacia National Conclave Materials, 1996-2000 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Officer Reports and Proposals, 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Other Chapter's Newsletters (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence with Other Chapters (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Kitchen Operations (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - AKAK Cup (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Acacia Car Decal, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Quartercards, 2000s (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Venerable Dean's Binder, 1976-1982 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Senior Dean, 1978-82 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1961-1982 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Constitutions (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Carpet Fund, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - House Betterment Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Little Sisters Program (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Daughters of Pythia Roll Book (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SMC Bills, 1990-1995 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer Files, 1990s (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer Files, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Masonic Promotional Materials, 1900s (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Pledge Manuals, 1980-2000s (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Rush, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Edwin Pena (Boarder) Local Philanthropy (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Philanthropy, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Acacia National Correspondence (Regional Leadership Conference), 1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Guest Speaker Program, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Other Chapter Publications (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Housing Agreements (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Thomas Lee Rickets Venerable Dean Papers (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - The Dippo Files (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Acacia National Promotional Materials (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Acacia Scholarship Information, 1993-2009 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - FY Receipts, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - FY Receipts, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Bank Accounts and Bills (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Bills, 2002-2003 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Bills, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Checks, 2004-2005 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - FY Receipts, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - FY Finances, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - FY Expenses and Tax Forms, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Checks, 2001-2002 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Checks, 2002-2003 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer Files, 2002-2003 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer Ledger, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Pledge Manual and Fraternity Experience, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Series IV. Corporation
  - Life Insurance Correspondence - F.O. Underwood, 1940-45 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Life Insurance Correspondence and Policies, 1942-82 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Life Insurance -- Individual Policies (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Life Insurance Policy: Ramey, Blaine & Davies (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Building Fund Correspondence and Records, Actives, 1950 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Keep-Acacia-Ahead Campaign (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Building Fund Reports (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Class Lists with Addresses and Pledges (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1982 Alumni Director (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Class Lists D. Marble, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Who's Who in Acacia by Roll #, May 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Building Fund Correspondence, Alumni, 1958 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Checks, Bills, etc, 1941-1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, 1970-75 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Bills, Bills Since 1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Bank Books, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Corp. Treasurer-Bank Statement, 1969-1975 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Corp. Treasurer - Budgets, 1963-1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Honorary Membership (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Alumni Correspondence, General (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Corp. Correspondences, Internal (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Corp. Correspondence, Outside, 1960-1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Corp. Correspondence Outside, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Outside Correspondence, 1991-2007 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - National Correspondence with Chapter Adviser (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - National Correspondence with Corp Board (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Corporation Constitutions (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Stewart Howe Alumni Agency Invoices; Invoices, 1969-1974; 1939-1972 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Stewart Howe Alumni Agency, Record of Transmittal of Financial Records, 1967-1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Housing Contracts, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Agreement with 316 Highland Road Apt. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - SMC Documentation (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Capital Expenditures and Quotes, 1966-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Electrical Outlet Report, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Workman's Comp. Papers and Insurance Policies (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Fire of 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Simplex Documentation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Showacre's Revolving Capital Reserve Fund, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Acacia Building Assessments, 1950-1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Corporation Board Minutes, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Corporation Board Minutes, 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Corporation Board Minutes, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Corporation Board Minutes, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Corporation Board Minutes, 2000-2007 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dues Forms, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dues Forms, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dues Forms, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Dues Forms, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Dues Forms, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Corporation Treasurer - Receipts and Expenditures, 1934-1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2010-2011 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2011-2012 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2011-2012 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Corporation Treasurer Records, 2012-2013 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2013-2014 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Corporation Treasurer Receipts, 2014-2015 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Corporation Operational Business, 2012-2014 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Corporation Board - Treasurer's Statements, 2005-2012 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Alumni Correspondence I, 2009-2010 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Alumni Correspondence II, 2009-2010 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Alumni Correspondence Capital Campaign, 2009 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 2010-2014 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Centennial Capital Campaign Donation Pledge Forms, 2007-2012 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Centennial Registration (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Acacia National Correspondence, 2010s (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Corporation Board Agendas and Attendance records, 2005-2010 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Corporation Meetings, Agendas, etc., 2011-2013 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Corporation Business Correspondence, 2010s (Box 24, Folder 23)
- Series V. Photographs
  - Photographs, 1921-1930 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Photographs, 1941-1950 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1951-1960 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Photographs, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Photographs, 1971-1980 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Human Service Project – Ithaca High School, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Photographs, 1981-1990 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Photographs, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, 1991-2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Photographs, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Acacia Fire, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Corporation Treasurer – Receipts and Expenditures (reproduction), 1934-1975 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Misc. House Management, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Alumni Database Updates, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Photographs, 2001-2010 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Oversized, 1900-1910 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized, 1911-1920 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Oversized, 1921-1930 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oversized, 1931-1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Oversized, 1941-1950 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Oversized, 1951-1960 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Oversized, 1961-1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Oversized, 1971-1980 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Oversized, Scrapbook, 1940s (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Oversized, Small Composites, 1963-2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Oversized, 1981-1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Oversized, 2000-2007 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Acacia Photo Album, January 1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Composite Reproductions, 1907-2006 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Early 1960s Photo Album (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - 1977 Photo Album (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Middle 1990s Photos (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Mid 1990s Photos, Middle 1990s (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - David Lewandowski Sympathy Book (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1994-1995 Photo Album by Jason Wang (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Early 2000s Scrapbook (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Series VI. Chapter Meeting Minutes (CMM)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes, 1923-1941 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book, 1941-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book, 1955-1964 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book, 1964-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book, 1976-1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Composition Book (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Typed Chapter Meeting Minutes-transcribed by Bradley Ayres, 1976 - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book-originals, 1986-1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes in book-incomplete originals, 2000-2007 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Notes on Chapter Meeting Minutes (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Chapter Meeting Minutes, 2007-2015 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Series VII. Publications: Traveler, 1912-2007
  - Traveler, Copies, 1912-1924 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Traveler, Copies, 1924-1933 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Traveler, Copies, 1946-1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Traveler, Copies, 1990-2007 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Traveler, Originals, 2011-2020 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1910s (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1920s (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1920s (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1920s (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1920-1930s (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1930-1940s (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1940-1960 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1970-1980s (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Traveler, Originals, 1990-2000s (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Traveler, Originals, 2000-2010 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Traveler, Originals, 2010-2020 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXVI. No. 1, 1946 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXVI. No. 2, 1947 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXVII. No. 1, 1947 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXVII. No. 2, 1948 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXIX. No. 1, 1949 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XXX. No. 1, 1950 (Box 20)
  - The Traveler. Vol. XIII. No. 1, 1926 (Box 21)
- Series VIII. TRIAD, Journal, 1906-1924
  - TRIAD, 1906-1911 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - TRIAD, 1908, 1915, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - TRIAD, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - TRIAD, 1915-1917 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - TRIAD, 1917-1922 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - TRIAD, 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - TRIAD, 1922-1924 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - TRIAD, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - TRIAD, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1924-1926 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - TRIAD, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - TRIAD, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - TRIAD, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - TRIAD, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - TRIAD, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - TRIAD, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Acacia Directory, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - TRIADs: Cornell References, 1931-1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - TRIAD, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - TRIAD, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - TRIAD, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - TRIAD, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - TRIAD, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1959-1960 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Banta's Greek Exchange, April 1964 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Bound TRIAD, 1966-1970 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - TRIAD, April 1968 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - TRIAD, 1988, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - TRIAD, 2010s (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Series IX. Chapter Membership Records
  - Volume I Roll #1-300 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Volume II Roll #301-589 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Reproductions of Roll # 488- 589 (Box 12, Folder 74)
- Series X. Brother Membership Files, Brother membership files contain information about each named Acacia fraternity member. Some of the materials include correspondence with the chapter or other brothers, essays written prior to initiation about expectations for the event, and announcements of birth, marriage, and death. Alumni dues notices are included. Some of the original folders were empty and in the case of the empty folders, a list of these additional Acacia members is provided after Series XI.
  - Abbey, Benton Gregg (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Abbey, Chas. N. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Abbey, Hobart A (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Adams, A. V. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Adsit, Charles H (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Agel, Frank O. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ahearn, William C. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Ahlfeld, John (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ahlfeld, Richard B. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Albrectson, R. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Alden, Fred N. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Aldrich, Leon C. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Alexander, Ivan Grant (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Amatulli, Ladis W. (Box 12, Folder 17)